cytiva.com 2012-04-02

# Privacy Policy

Effective November 11, 2009

Taleo Corporation and its affiliated companies (Taleo) provides this Web Site Privacy Statement to explain how we collect, use, and disclose certain personal information online. Taleo also has a separate privacy statement that applies to certain personal data that Taleo receives in the United States from the European Union and Switzerland, called the Safe Harbor Privacy Statement.

This Web Site Privacy Statement discloses the privacy practices for Taleo.com. Taleo Corporation is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent organization whose mission is to advance privacy and trust in the networked world. As Taleo wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed, with respect to this Web site, to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices monitored for compliance by TRUSTe.

The TRUSTe program only covers information that is collected through this Web site, and does not cover information that may be collected through any software downloaded from this Web site.

This Website Privacy Statement notifies you of:

  * The organization collecting the information;
  * What personally identifiable information is collected from you through this Web site;
  * How the information may be used;
  * What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information;
  * With whom the information may be shared;
  * The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information under Taleo control; and
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Web Site Privacy Statement, you should first contact [newfeedback@taleo.com](mailto:newfeedback@taleo.com "opens your email
program") by email. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe through its [Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url= "opens new tab/window"). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with Taleo to resolve your concerns.

Generally, you can visit Taleo on the Web without telling us who you are or revealing any personally identifiable information about yourself. We collect no such information about you when you visit our sites, unless you choose to provide that information to us.

The types of Personal Information we may collect about you through our sites include contact and identifying information (name, address, email address, phone and fax numbers, institution, title or job position), information about your interest in Taleo products or services, information about your interest in newsletters, seminars, or other services that we provide (solely or jointly with others), information provided in connection with the registration of your organization for certain solutions (such as Taleo Business Edition and Taleo Enterprise), information about other transactions that you or your organization may enter with Taleo, and any other Personal Information that you may provide to us in an online form or through an email.

Where we collect Personal Information through online forms, we will notify you of which fields are mandatory for the particular service or functionality you are requesting (i.e., through the use of an asterisk (*) next to such mandatory field), and which fields are optional. If you choose to provide information that is optional, we may use and disclose such information for the purposes described below.

We may use Personal Information to provide newsletters and other requested information, to register you for seminars as requested, to answer questions and inquiries, to conduct activities in connection with the performance of requested or ongoing transactions, to conduct surveys in which you elect to participate, and where appropriate, to provide you with further information about our products and services.

#### Agents

We may use an outside shipping company to fulfill orders, and a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purposes.

#### Financial Information

We offer some limited products (such as Taleo Business Edition) and event registration that you may wish to purchase online. To complete these online financial transactions, our sites may request Personal Information including contact information (such as name, title, email address or shipping address) and credit card billing information. Disclosure of this information is completely voluntary and you have a choice whether or not to disclose this information.

#### Surveys & Contests

From time-to-time our sites may request Personal Information from you in connection with surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Personal Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes, and may also be used to provide you with additional information about our products or services, or those of our selected business partners.

#### Bulletin Boards/Chat Rooms

If you use a bulletin board, discussion forum, or chat room on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. There are also testimonials from our clients on this site. They have consented to showing their personally identifiable information as part of the testimonial.

#### Career Section Registration

Our Candidate Profiler requires a valid email address as a login. This permits us to contact you if your job preferences match any job opportunities posted at our site. Except for a valid email address and geographical location information, all other information you are asked to submit is optional and voluntary. For example, candidates may voluntarily choose to attach a resume to their profile, or opt to receive notifications about future job openings from Taleo. We will make this Personal Information available to our recruiters and select employees worldwide, as well as third parties, such as background checking organizations, as necessary or appropriate based on a relevant business need to know.

#### "Send this to a friend" Option

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. We use the information you provided for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.

#### Log Files and Aggregate Information

Like most standard Web site servers, we collect and use IP addresses from browsing machines to analyze trends, administer the site, track pages that have been viewed, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. Taleo does not link this information with Personal Information about individual users. We reserve the right to share aggregate and anonymous information with potential partners and other third parties without restriction.

#### Use of Cookies and Clear Gifs

Our sites may use cookies to enhance your experience while visiting our sites. Cookies are pieces of information transferred to the browsing computer and used for record-keeping purposes. Cookies generally assist users by performing certain functions such as saving passwords and personal preferences regarding the sites. Cookies are linked to personally identifiable information. Many consider the use of cookies to be an industry standard.

Your browser is probably set to accept cookies. However, if you would prefer not to receive cookies, you can alter the configuration of your browser to refuse cookies. If you choose to have your browser refuse cookies, it is possible that some areas of our sites will not function properly when you view them.

Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Taleo only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

We employ a third-party product called Eloqua which uses a software technology called clear gifs (also known as Web beacons or Web bugs), that help us provide better content on our site by informing us what content is effective.  Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to generate an anonymous notice of a visit by a Web user.  In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages. We use these technologies to provide you with the products and services you requested or with offers or promotions that may interest you and to save you time. We tie the information gathered by clear gifs to information about your company and the personal information you have provided to us.

  To learn more about Eloqua’s use of clear gifs, please go to <http://www.eloqua.com/>.

  We also use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients.  This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns.  If you would like to opt-out of these emails, or any other communications, you may email us at [newfeedback@taleo.com](mailto:newfeedback@taleo.com?subject=Subcription%20Removal).

#### Disclosures of Personal Information

We may disclose Personal Information as necessary or appropriate in connection with any of the purposes for which we use Personal Information, including to subcontractors or service providers that help host or support the sites or otherwise provide technical assistance, fulfillment companies that help us to provide requested products or services, and business partners that help conduct seminars or otherwise provide requested products, services, or information. We also reserve right to disclose Personal Information in connection with the sale or transfer of all or part of the business. In these situations where we transfer Personal Information to these types of third parties, we require by contract that such third parties must not use or disclose the information for any purposes other than those specified in this Website Privacy Policy, and that such third parties must maintain commercially reasonable security measures to protect the Personal Information. In situations involving the sale or transfer of all or part of the business, we will seek to notify users of the ownership change by way of a prominent notice posted on our Web site. We also reserve the right to disclose Personal Information in connection with any judicial or administrative orders, law enforcement requests, or other applicable legal requirements.

#### Links

Our Web Sites may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that Taleo is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites, and this Web Site Privacy Statement does not apply to such sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information.

Taleo takes reasonable technical and organizational measures to protect the security of our users' Personal Information. When a secure form asks users to enter Personal Information, that information is encrypted and protected with the encryption software standard in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just 'surfing'. To learn more about SSL, please visit [www.comodogroup.com](http://www.comodogroup.com/ "opens new tab/window").

While we use SSL encryption to protect certain financial information online, we also take reasonable steps to protect user information off-line. All of our users' Personal Information, not just the financial information mentioned above, is subject to restricted access in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, a customer service representative or sales representative) are granted access to Personal Information. Our employees must use passwords to gain access to Personal Information. Furthermore, all employees are regularly informed about our security and privacy practices. When new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to protect our users' and customers' Personal Information. Finally, we maintain reasonable technical and organizational measures to make sure that the servers on which we store Personal Information are kept in an access-restricted, physically secure, and monitored environment.

If you have any questions about the security at our website, you can send an email to [infosecurity@taleo.com](mailto:infosecurity@taleo.com "opens
your email program").

#### Changes to this Web Site Privacy Statement

If we decide to change this Web Site Privacy Statement, we will post the revised policy at this location, or at another location that is accessible via link from our homepages, so that users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use Personal Information in a manner that is substantially different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will seek to notify users by way of an email, and provide users with a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner.

#### Unsubscribe or Modify Information

We intend to protect the quality and integrity of your Personal Information. If your Personal Information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), and you wish to update or delete the Personal Information that we maintain about you, please email our Web Producer at [newfeedback@taleo.com](mailto:newfeedback@taleo.com?subject=Feedback%20from%20Website "opens your email program"). Also, if you wish to unsubscribe from any of our newsletters or other communications, you may also email us at [newfeedback@taleo.com](mailto:newfeedback@taleo.com?subject=Feedback%20from%20Website "opens your email program"). TRUSTe requires a response to an access request provided within 30 days of submitting the request.

#### Contact Information

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:

**Taleo Corporation**  
Attention: Legal Department / Privacy Office  
4140 Dublin Boulevard, 4th Floor  
Dublin, CA 94568  
United States  
Phone: 1.888.836.3669  
Fax: 1.925.452.3027  
Email: [Taleo Privacy Office](mailto:privacyofficer@taleo.com?subject=Taleo%20Privacy%20Office "opens your email program")

Back To Top

This Statement describes how Taleo Corporation and its affiliated companies ("Taleo") collects, uses, and discloses certain personally identifiable information that it receives in the United States from the European Union and Switzerland ("EU and Swiss Personal Data"). In particular, Taleo recognizes that the European Union and Switzerland have established strict protections regarding the handling of EU and Swiss Personal Data, and Taleo therefore has elected to adhere to the US-EU Safe Harbor Privacy Principles and US-Switzerland Safe Harbor Privacy Principles (together, the "Safe Harbors") with respect to such EU and Swiss Personal Data that it receives in the United States. For further background and information about the Safe Harbors, and to see Taleo's representation on the Safe Harbor List, please refer to the U.S. Department of Commerce's website at [www.export.gov/safeharbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/ "opens
new tab/window").

In general, Taleo may obtain EU and Swiss Personal Data in the United States about several different types of individuals, including (i) website visitors, (ii) clients, suppliers, and business partners, (iii) candidates for employment with clients, and (iv) Taleo's own employees. Taleo's practices with respect to each of these types of individual data subjects are described below.

#### Website Visitors

Taleo generally collects, uses, and discloses information about website visitors located in the EU or Switzerland in accordance with the Website Privacy Policy at www.taleo.com/privacy/privacy-policy.

#### Clients, Suppliers, and Business Partners

Taleo may obtain various types of EU and Swiss Personal Data about employees and agents of our clients, suppliers, and business partners. Such data may include contact information (names, titles, addresses, phone and fax numbers, and email addresses); information about products and services ordered or provided; financial and payment information; user ID, passwords, and information collected through Internet-based and e-commerce activities, and other transaction-related data.

Taleo may use these types of EU and Swiss Personal Data for business purposes, including to deliver or provide products or services; to establish or maintain client and business relationships; to provide access to Internet-based and e-commerce activities; to perform accounting functions; and to conduct other activities as necessary or appropriate in connection with the servicing and development of the business relationship.

Employees and agents of our clients, business partners, and suppliers may contact us if any of their EU and Swiss Personal Data changes, or if they would like to access and correct EU and Swiss Personal Data that we maintain about them. However, such persons might first wish to contact their local human resources representative (i.e. the human resources representative within our Clients), as that might be the most efficient means of addressing their issues. In any event, such persons can also contact us by sending an email to [Taleo Privacy Office](mailto:privacyofficer@taleo.com?subject=Taleo%20Privacy%20Office "opens your email program"), or by using the information at the end of this privacy statement. Also, to the extent that any of these individuals receive marketing communications from Taleo, and wish to unsubscribe or otherwise stop receiving such communications, they can contact us at [newfeedback@taleo.com](mailto:newfeedback@taleo.com?subject=Feedback%20from%20Website "opens your email program").

#### Candidates for Employment with Clients

Taleo provides a wide variety of services and solutions to its business clients ("Clients") that facilitate recruiting, hiring, compensation, performance management and internal mobility of individuals ("Data Subjects"). In some instances, Taleo may obtain access to EU and Swiss Personal Data about such Data Subjects in the course of providing the services and solutions. In other specific instances, Taleo may also obtain access to data about our Clients' existing employees or end users in the course of providing support services to the Clients ("End Users"). Such data may include contact details, work history, educational history, work preferences, and other information, depending on the particular Client and application at issue.

Wherever we obtain access to EU and Swiss Personal Data about Data Subjects or End Users, we are acting as a mere data processor on behalf of our Clients, and we therefore conduct such activities strictly in accordance with their instructions and pursuant to our contractual arrangements with them. If you are a candidate for employment with one of our Clients, an employee of one of our Clients, or an End User with an existing relationship with one of our Clients, you should refer to the Client's website or human resources manager to understand the privacy practices that apply to EU and Swiss Personal Data that we may maintain about you. Moreover, if you would like to access and review your EU and Swiss Personal Data, you should contact our Client (your potential or existing employer) with any such requests. We will cooperate as appropriate with requests from our Clients to assist with such responses.

#### Taleo Employees

Taleo employees located in the European Union should consult with their local human resources manager to obtain information about Taleo's practices with respect their EU and Swiss Personal Data. Online job applicants to Taleo should also consult any additional terms that apply when they submit their applications and/or resumes.

Taleo may disclose EU and Swiss Personal Data to business partners and subcontractors as necessary in connection with the performance of requested services or solutions, or as otherwise appropriate in connection with a legitimate business need. Taleo may also disclose EU and Swiss Personal Data as necessary in connection with the sale or transfer of all or part of the business. In these situations, Taleo will require the recipient of the data to protect the data in accordance with the relevant principles in the Safe Harbors, or otherwise take steps to ensure that the EU and Swiss Personal Data is appropriately protected. Taleo may also disclose EU and Swiss Personal Data where required or permitted by law, or where Taleo believes that such disclosures are appropriate in connection with a law enforcement request.

#### Data Security and Integrity

Taleo has global hosting centers that store and process EU and Swiss Personal Data in various locations in the United States, including California. Taleo takes reasonable precautions to protect EU and Swiss Personal Data in these centers and in other locations in the United States from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Taleo also makes reasonable efforts to keep EU and Swiss Personal Data reliable for its intended use, accurate, current, and complete.

#### Questions

If you have any questions about this afe Harbor Privacy Statement, or if you would like to request access to EU and Swiss Personal Data that we may maintain about you, please contact us as follows:

**Taleo Corporation**  
Attention: Legal Department / Privacy Office  
4140 Dublin Boulevard, 4th Floor  
Dublin, CA 94568  
United States  
Phone: 1.888.836.3669  
Fax: 1.925.452.3027  
Email: [Taleo Privacy Office](mailto:privacyofficer@taleo.com?subject=Taleo%20Privacy%20Office "opens your email program")

Any questions regarding this Safe Harbor Privacy Statement should first be directed to the Taleo contact above. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you may then contact the local data protection authorities in your EU member state or Switzerland for further information.
